The fish is very fresh today
今天的烤子~特e新r
Eat up, enjoy yourself
你e客猓多吃c
Sorry to interrupt your dinner
不好意思，打_你吃
Never mind, let's sit over there
不要o，我^那坐
It's quite late
怎N@油恚
I've just finished work
是啊，下班
What should I call you?
怎NQ呼你
You can call me Mrs. Suen
叫我O太太
And you?
你呢？
My husband's name is Chan
我先生姓
Call me when you decide I will
- Q定了就o我 - 好的
Did you write down my number?
有]有把a抄下
Yes, I did
抄下了
Fine, I'll see you out
那好，我送你出去
Don't trouble No trouble
- 不用了 - 要的，大家上海人嘛
So it's agreed then
那N就@Q定了
Thank you very much, I should go
xx你，我先走了
Fine Bye
- 好的 - 再
Take care, goodbye
慢走，再
You've a room to let?
@e是不是有房g出租？
Sorry, it's just been rented to that lady
真Σ黄穑租o那位太太
Thanks
xx你
How many of you?
你人住？
Just me and my wife
我跟我太太人
Why don't you try next door
你不妨到隔壁看
They've a vacant room too?
隔壁有房g出租幔
Yes, Mr.Koo's son got married
是，隔壁先生的鹤Y婚
and removed out
搬了出去
His room's empty
房g也想找人租
Thank you
xx你
You're too polite, Try asking them
不客猓你管
This way, come on
恚@e
Not that room
@不是我的
Wrong again
怎N搞的，真麻
Careful, against the wall there
先靠放著，小心啊
The little cupboard over there
小子靠在那
Be careful
慢慢
Don't break anything
小心，e碰e人的|西
Not on top of the radio
e牧耸找C
Mr.Chow
周先生
You have a lot of stuff for a couple
怎N家俱@佣啵
The wardrobe isn't mine, wrong again?
- @不是我的 - 又搬e？
It does next door
是不是隔壁的？
Okay, next door
那搬回去，搬回去
There aren't my shoes
@些鞋子不是我的，是不是拿e了
They must go next door
我想是隔壁的，拿^去吧
What a coincidence, moving in on same day
真是巧，搬家都碰在一起
Is Mr.Chan here?
怎N]看你先生？
He's working abroad
公司有事派他出T了
He'll be back next week
下Y拜才回
You should have waited, then
那你等他回碓侔崧
It's too much for you on your own
搬家那N辛苦，你一人付得了幔
I can manage I'll ask Amah to help
- 我可以的 - 叫王兔
No need, I can manage
e客猓O太太，我自己行的
What's going on?
怎N回事？
Mind that mirror
小心那R子
Mrs. Chan, I'll leave you to it
太太，你^m收拾好了
Those books aren't mine Wrong again?
- @些不是我的 - 又e了？
Never mind, just leave them there
不要o，先放下吧
Mind how you hang the mirror it's fragile
@小心放，@些砸的
Are these magazines yours?
@些sI是不是你的？
Yes, they're my husband's
是的，我先生的
He reads Japanese?
你先生懂日文啊？
A little, his boss is Japanese
懂一c，他老是日本人
How should I address you?
]教你F姓？
My husband's name is Chan
我先生姓
My name's Chow... I'll leave you in peace
我姓周，我先回去了
Thank you, Mr.Chow
xx你周先生
Don't mention it
不客
I'll ask Mrs. Chan...
我去叫太太
Mrs. Chan, eat with us before you go
太太，跟我一起吃吧
No thanks, I must dash to the airport
我不吃了，我srg，我得去C
Your husband's coming back? Yes
- 你先生回砹耍 - 是的
Then I won't keep you
那我不耽`你了
Going out? Yes
- 出去呀？ - 晚安
Sorry, I'm late
Σ黄穑我t了
Amah, pour some beer
王，快c倒酒
Cheers
乾杯
Mrs. Chow, try some Shanghai dishes
- 周太太，L一L我的上海家常菜 - 我自己砭托辛
Where is Mrs. Chan to so late?
太太到哪e去了？
Meeting here husband at the airport
她去接wC嘛，她先生回砹
So that's why she looks different
怪不得打扮得那N漂亮
It's all packed, take care on your trip
我都湍闶帐昂昧耍你自己小心c
I will
知道了
How long this time?
你@回去好久幔那N多|西？
Two to four weeks
是呀，要一月
Remember when you come back
你得回淼r候
Bring back two more of those handbags
你上回送o我的皮包
Who for?
l要？
Mr.Boss
我老
Two of them?
那N多？
You know why
你知道啦
Different colours?
那要不要同色？
The same will do? Who cares?
一宇色行了，管它呢
Whatever
龋可是你f的
Mrs. Ho
何太太幔课沂翘K秘呀
Mr.Ho is still in a meeting
何先生F在在事情
He'll be home late
他f今晚晚回家
Please don't wait to eat
叫你e等他吃
Yes, we're so busy at the moment
是啊，我@子很忙
Yes, I'll ask him to call you when he gets back
我他忙完了o你打
Did you call my wife?
o我太太打^了？
Yes, I said you'd be back later
打^了，我f你晚一c回去
Have you booked the restaurant?
臀矣了位]有？
A table for two at eight
了，八c晌
Miss Yu called to say
余小姐黼，她fR上要出T
she's on her way
叫你快c
I'll be back after dinner
吃^我就回
can I bring you something?
要不要c|西o你吃
No thanks, I'll get my own
不客猓我自己出去吃就行了
Leave when you're ready
如果你k完事情我]回
I'll lock up
你先走，我礞iT好了
Good evening, Mr.Ho Evening
何先生，你走了？
Going out, Mrs. Chan Yes
- 太太，出去呀？ - 是的
Going out so late?
@r候要出去呀？
Just getting some noodles
我去I面
Amah is making pork soup, join us
王在弄蹄膀，大家一K吃
Thanks, I'm not really hungry I just want some air
e客猓我不是太I，我想出去走走
You're too polite Next time
- 不要客饴 - 下次吧
They're all starving, we can eat
王，三哥他都I了，我吃吧
Have you spoken to Ming?
跟明哥f了]有？
So I'll go with someone else
那N我跟e人去
Just kidding
v著玩的
I'll be early tonight, see you soon
我早c下班，你也早c回
Bye
- 再 - 再
Chow
阿周
Coming
砝
Time to go, finish it tomorrow
周，下班了，|西留著明天做
No, I'm nearly there
做的差不多了，弄完再走了
Oh, Ming
明哥
I need a few days off next month why?
- 我下月想滋旒 - 质颤N？
I promised my wife a trip
答跟太太去旅行，都f了好啄
Put in a word for me, will you?
你臀
I'll speak to personnel
好吧，我跟人事部vv
But the next lunch is on you
不^，你可要吃
I'll
怎佣夹
Thanks, Ming
多x你明哥
It's ready
好了，好了
No, it'll switch itself off
]呢，熟了那I跳起
I told you, it's not ready
哪有@N快，你@l下人
A rice cooker, It's yours, Mrs. Koo?
啊，新I的，太太？
No, it's beyond us
像我@些老古板
It's Mrs. Chan's
哪缘觅I@N|西，是太太的
My husband brought it from Japan
我先生娜毡Щ淼
I wanted to show Mrs. Koo how good it is
我看挺好，所以介Bo太太
Now it's ready
跳起砹耍跳起砹
It's workable, you can see
@回真行了，你看多方便
Mrs. Chan
太太
Could Mr.Chan get me one next time?
麻┠汴先生，下次臀б回
No problem
好，]}
Mr.Chow, you should get one too
周先生，你也I上一
Your wife's so often late home
你太太老是值夜班，有了它就方便多了
I couldn't trouble Mr.Chan
麻╆先生不太好意思
It's just neighborly, isn't it?
隔壁居，o所^啦
It's no trouble
不要o，他^商再去
I'll ask him to buy another next time
我叫他多б回
Thank you
那N多x你了
Let's try the rice
恚我LL
Mr.Chan, sorry to trouble you about the rice cooker
真不好意思，要你老hщo我
It was really no trouble
手的嘛，用不著客
How much do I owe you?
]付X你，多少X？
Your wife has already paid me
你太太已o我了
Really?
是幔
She didn't tell you?
她]告V你？
She's been working late shifts
她@子值夜班
Often I'm asleep when she gets back
等她回砦乙呀睡了
It must be hard for her
在酒店做事也真辛苦
Yes
是啊
Mrs. Chan isn't back yet?
太太]回恚
She'll be back soon, you need to talk to her
我想她快回砹耍你有事找她？
A friend needs to go to Singapore
我有朋友^商烊バ录悠
I wonder if she could get a cheap ticket for him
想看看太太的公司有]有 便宜c的船票
I'll ask when she gets back
等她回砦腋嬖V她
I'm bothering you too much
麻┠不好意思
Don't mention it, we're neighbors
客什N猓大家隔壁居，的
I'll leave you in peace
那N我先回去了
Looking for me?
怎N，找我？
Damn right, where've you been?
打著找呢，整上午到哪喝チ耍
What's up?
什N事呀？
Mrs. Chan called
太太打
you left a hat at her office
f你把帽子忘在她公司了
I meant to, I wanted an excuse to go back
我故意的，不然哪有C多看她裳
I know your tricks
早知你磉@一手
she's married
人家可是有老公的
I know
我然知道她有老公
That's why I left
要不我回致
otherwise I'd move in next door
乾脆搬到你那喝
If your wife wasn't so attractive
f真的，幸好你老婆也是美人
She'd be a worried woman
要不然我可要替她心
I'm not like you
你我是你啊
Please call Mrs. Chan for me
臀掖螂s太太
I'll pick up the hat tomorrow
f我明天上她公司拿帽子
And take her to lunch
便她喝茶
Dream on, I asked her to
你想得美
take the hat home
我跟她f了，把帽子先拿回家
I'll bring it in tomorrow
明早我湍Щ
You're kidding, some buddy you are
真猓是老朋友呢
Tell you what, let's go pick up now
索性我跟你回家去
She should be off work by now
@c下班了
We can go together
一K航铀下班去
I don't have time for this
械酶你v
Chow
阿周
Yes, get out of here, I'm busy
砝玻快走吧，我要忙
Then I'll wait at your place
@影桑我先走，在家等你
That's all
就@Nf定了
Ping
炳，炳
Mr.Chow, is Mr.Koo in?
周先生，先生在不在？
He's out, forgot to buy the paper again?
他出去了，又忘了I蠹了?
That's right, I'll stop by later
是，我待涸
Maybe I can find it for you Thank you
- 我湍阏艺铱 - xx你
This one? Yes
- 是@一幔 - 是的
I always loved those serials, hated to miss an episode
我以前也常看的，一天不看就不自在
Really? You like them too?
是幔磕阋蚕g看武b小f？
I even thought of writing one
迷^一子，我想^自己
Why didn't you?
槭颤N]
I couldn't get started, so I gave up
想硐肴ラ_不了^，也就算了
I wasn't born to write martial arts stories
注定不是诌@一行的
But you can borrow from my collection any time
那些武b小f我都留著，要看你拿去
Not now, maybe another time, thanks
不了，下回再麻┠悖xx你
You're welcome
不客
What is it, Mrs. Chan?
什N事，太太？
I just want to return these to Mr.Chow is he in?
@些o周先生的，他在不在家？
He's been away for a few days
他好滋]回
Why?
怎N回事？
They had a quarrel
煞蚱蕹臣芰
Leave them with me
你把R下吧，等周先生回
I'll pass them back to him
我湍氵o他
Thank you
xx
Forget it
不用了
I'm on a replacement shift tonight
今晚我值夜班
Talk to you later
你先回去吧
No need to pick me up
再f吧，今晚我t一c， 你不用斫游伊
She's already left
她已走啦
Really? I was going to take her out for supper
是幔想接她一K吃夜宵
Didn't she tell you she was off early today
她]告V你幔克今天早下班
She never remembers to tell me
她老是@樱三倒四的
Maybe she's home by now
f不定已回到家e了
I'll be off, then
那我先走了
Okay, bye
好的，再
Hello
你好
You're out of hospital
你出院了幔
Don't mention hospital, Lend me $30
先ef了，借我三十K
What for?
质颤N？
You gotta help me save face
兔Γ名u攸P
What's the big deal?
出了什N大事？
It's Ah Hoi's fault
不是那阿海，那天磲t院看我
He gave me a racing tip, said it was a sure thing
f有饶幌息，A的
Before they'd taken out the stitches
我看他那N有把握，都聿患安
I rushed from hospital to Race Course
一股排艹鲠t院，s去R
I bet everything I had
把老婆本都押上了
and I lost my shirt
Y果了精光
What did you expect?
活，_完刀要去
I thought it was my lucky day
我想上，必有大\
Anyhow, I had only $2 left
l知剩KX
So I went to the whorehouse
饩团苋フ屹F妃
You were in no shape for sex
病到@幼幽氵要去玩女人啊？
I thought it would improve for sex
想__喜嘛
What would $2 buy you?
不是只剩KX？幔
I'm Kwai Fei's regular, she gives me credit
我是常客，好商量，先d著也可以的
You can have in on credit?
@N事情也可以d~？
I left my ID card and
把身份C押o她
said I'd be back to redeem it
f好扇天後回去拿
I thought a few dollars would be back easy to rustle up
原以檫@N一cX很容易
But so far nothing I'm way overdue
l知到F在]搞定，^了期
So?
那怎k？
Four Eyes was there yesterday
怎k？昨盒∷纳先
Saw her waving my ID around in
可不就看她拿著我那身份C
front of everyone
到人看
So embarrassing
你f衰不衰啊？
Anyway, lend me $30
先ef了，o我三十K
This is all can spare
我只有那N多
I need $10 for myself
留十K，@些你拿去用
Pay you back next month
月初就你
Let's have a late snack What?
- 去吃宵夜 - 要吃宵夜？
All I've had today is some won-ton noodles
一整天就吃了一碗吞I，都快I死了
Let me finish writing this first
等我好@一段吧
I'm not sure I should tell you this
有件事，我不知道要不要跟你f
What?
什N事？
I saw your wife in the street yesterday
昨天在街上看你老婆
So what?
@有什N好奇怪的？
That is nothing
奇怪倒不奇怪
but she was with some guy
不^她好像跟一男人走在一起
Probably a friend
可能是她朋友
Just thought you should know
f得也Γ我不^是S便ff而已
Miss Yu? This is me
余小姐幔我是K秘啊
Mr.Ho's still in a meeting
何先生在事情
he says he can't manage dinner
他f晚上恐怕不能跟你吃
Yes, we're very busy now
是，我@子很忙
I'll, I'll ask Mr.Ho to call
好的，我跟他f，再
Have you called Miss Yu? Yes, I've
- 你跟余小姐f了]有？ - f^了
What did she say?
她怎Nf？
Asks you to call her later
她叫你晚一co她
And Mrs. Ho says she's ready to cut her birthday cake
何太太磉^，f快切蛋糕了
She wants you to hurry home
叫你快回去
Did you get me something to give her? Yes, this
- Y物I了]有？ - I了
What is it? A scarf
- 是什N|西？ - 是巾
I think Mrs. Ho will like it Thank you
- 我想何太太喜g吧 - 麻┠懔
And here's your change
用剩的X
I'm always troubling you
不用了，你拿著，老是麻┠
use it for bus fare
M也要的
Why don't you dine with us tonight?
不如，到我家吃D便？
Thank you, I've already planned to see a film tonight
e客猓我s了我先生看影
Then I won't keep you
那就不妨K你了
Tomorrow will be quiet
明天上午]什N事
take the morning off
你可以下午才回
Goodbye goodbye
- 再 - 再
Are you going out tonight?
你今天晚上出去幔
Don't forget your keys
得拿匙
All the neighbors are dining out tonight
O太太他去吃喜酒
I have a lot to do here so I'll be late
公司很忙，我晚c回
What is it, Mrs. Chan?
什N事，太太
I heard voices
我隔壁有音
I thought Mr.& Mrs. Koo were back
以槭穷先生太太回
Not yet, anything I can help with?
]有，你找他有事？
No, I just wanted a chat
]什N，找他聊聊天
Are you alone? Yes, I am
- 你一人？ - 是
You're back early today
@N早回恚
I'm not feeling well, I came back to rest
有c不舒服，就早c回砹
What is it? I have some medicines
你哪e不舒服，我有
Don't trouble yourself, I'll sleep it off
不用了，我睡壕秃
In that case, I'll leave you in peace
好，我不打_了
It was your wife
你的老婆
Have you spoken to your wife yet?
跟你老婆f了]有？
Then we shouldn't meet any more
那N你以後e再找我
Any news from the Philippines?
菲律e那有]有消息
Yes, a telex
收到
There's a typhoon, so the ship's still docked
f那刮UL，船都不能_
Please inform Chan
那N你R上通知先生
That the shipment may be delayed
f他那批可能要晚一商觳拍艿
Ask if that's a problem
他有]有}
Your wife rang
何太太打^
you don't need to pick her up
f用不著回家去接她
She's playing mahjong with Mrs. Lau
她在跟⑻太打牌
She'll meet you at the restaurant at 5:30
你五c半直接上天香钦宜便行
and there's a gift from Miss Yu
余小姐有一份Y物交o你
She was here?
她上磉^？
No, she had it sent over
不，她找人送上淼
She says she'll dine alone since it's your birthday
她f知道你今天生日，酬多
Please phone her
所以不找你吃了
when you have a moment
叫你有空再o她
I'll get you another coffee Thank you
- 我湍愕贡咖啡 - xx
Thank you
xx
That tie looks good on you
IШ芷亮
You noticed?
你看得出我Q了I幔
It's much like the old one
我以椴畈欢
You notice things if you pay attention
仔看能看出
I'll be off now
我先走了
If Chan has a problem
如果先生那有}
let me know at the restaurant
打到天香钦椅
Why did you change your tie?
怎N把IвQ了？
The new one was too showy
我嫌那l太花俏了c
I should stick with my own
是Q回原淼暮
Don't forget to lock up
得iT啊
By the way, haven't seen your husband lately
α耍最近很少看你先生
He's abroad now, on company business
是呀，@子他公司有事，派了他出去
That's why I see you at the noodle stall
怪不得老在I碰你
I don't like cooking for myself
一人械弥箫
Haven't seen your wife lately either
α耍你太太呢？最近也很少看她
Her mother's ill, she's at home with her
她身w不太舒服，回娘家陪陪她
That explains it
y怪了
Good night Good night
- 晚安 - 晚安
Mrs. Chan, I'm glad you're back
太太，你回砭秃昧
It's raining so hard
外面雨下得那N
I was going to look for you with and umbrella
我想打闳ソ幽隳
You are too kind
不^是^雨，你有心
Amah, who is it?
王，是l？
It's Mrs. Chan
是太太
Mrs. Suen
O太太
Caught in the rain? I said you could
哎呀，下那N大雨出去呀
eat with us
大家自己人，早叫你一道吃
Next time, Enjoy your game
下回吧，慢慢打
Her husband's always away
哎呀，她先生一天到晚在外^
It's sad to see her to lonely
她一人孤伶伶怪可z的
She dresses up like that to go out for noodle
出去I碗I，穿得真漂亮
Mr.Chow, What are you doing here?
周先生，怎N到@砹耍
Just calling Mrs. Koo to the phone
我^斫蓄太太
You're late back
@N晚？
I went to the picture
看了鲭影
I'll be going
我先回去了
Hello
喂
Yes, please hold on
啊，你等等啊
Who is it? It's for Mrs. Chan
- 是l的？ - 太太的
It must seem odd to ask you out but I want to ask something
那N冒昧s你出恚是有c事想教你
That handbag I saw you with this evening
你今天下午拿著的皮包
Where did you buy it?
不知道哪e有的I？
Why do you ask?
你槭颤N@？
It looked so elegant
哦，我看款式很e@
I want to get one for my wife
想I一送o我太太
Mr.Chow, you're so good to your wife
周先生μ太真心
Not really, my wife is so fussy
那e，她@人很挑剔
Her birthday is two days away
^商焖生日
I don't know what to get her
不知道I什N送o她才好
Could you buy one for me to give her?
你可不可以臀屹I一？
Maybe she wouldn't want one just exactly the same
要是一模一拥模她不喜g吧
You're right, I didn't think of that
f的也是，我倒也]想到
Women would mind
女人介意，Π桑
Yes, especially since we're neighbors
的，特e是隔壁居
Do they come in other colors?
不知道不有e的色
I'd have to ask my husband
那要我先生才知道
Why?
槭颤N？
He bought it for me
那皮包是我先生
on a business trip abroad
在外地工作的r候Io我的
They aren't on sale here
他f在香港]有u的
Then never mind
那就算了吧
Actually
其
I want to ask your something too
我也有一件事情想教你
What?
什N事？
Where did you buy your tie?
你的Iг谀难eI的？
I don't know where it came from
我真的不知道
My wife buys all my ties
我I全是我太太臀屹I的
Really?
是幔
She bought this one
我想起砹耍有一次她公司派她出去
on a business trip abroad
回硭徒o我的
It's not on sale here
她f香港]有u的
What a coincidence
倒有@N巧
Yes
是啊
Actually
其
My husband has one just like it
我先生也有lIЦ你的一模一
He said it was a gift from his boss
他f是他老送他的
So he wears it every day
所以天天戴著
Any my wife has a bag just like yours
我太太也有皮包跟你那一模一
I know, I have seen it
我知道，我^
What are you getting at, actually?
你想f什N
I thought I was the only one who knew
我以橹挥形乙人知道
I wonder how it began
不知道他是怎娱_始的
It's late, won't your wife complain?
你@N晚不回家，你老婆不f你幔
She's used to it, she doesn't care
早T了，她不管我的
And your husband?
你呢？你老公不f什N幔
He must be asleep by now
我想他早睡了
Shall we stay out tonight?
今晚e回去了
My husband would never say that
我老公不@又v的
What would he say?
他怎Nv
Anyhow, he wouldn't say that
就是不v
Someone must have made the first move
有一人先_口吧
Who else could it be?
不是他是l？
It's late, won't your wife complain?
你@N晚不回家，你老婆不幔
She's used to it, she doesn't care
早T了，她不管的
And your husband?
你老公不f什N幔
He must be asleep by now
我想他早睡了
I can't say it
我真的f不出口
I understand
我明白
After all, it's already happened
事到如今
It doesn't matter who made the first move
l先_口有什N所^
Do you really know your wife?
其你知不知道你老婆是怎拥娜
You order for me
你臀尹c
Why?
槭颤N？
I've no idea what your wife likes
我想知道你老婆喜g吃什N
What about your husband?
那N你丈夫喜g吃什N
Like it hot?
吃得T幔
Your wife likes hot dishes
你老婆挺能吃辣的
Why did you call me at the office today?
槭颤N打到我公司？
I had nothing to do, I want to hear your voice
]事做，想你的音
You have my husband down pat
W得倒挺像我老公
He's real sweet-talker
油嘴滑舌
Why didn't you call me today?
你槭颤N不打o我？
I was afraid you won't like it
怕你不高d
Then don't call me again
那N以後不要再打o我
Mrs. Chan, a letter from your husband
太太，先生有封信砹耍你看看
It's not for me, it's for Mr.Chow next door
不是我的，是隔壁周先生的
The Japanese stamp made me think
我看信封上的日本]票
it was your husband
以槭顷先生寄
So I was wrong
原聿皇
Your wife's in Japan?
你老婆去了日本？
How did you know?
你怎N知道
What did she say in her letter?
信e些什N？
Nothing special
]什N
Anything about when she'd be back?
有]有fr回恚
No
]有
What do you think they're doing right now?
你猜他F在在做什N？
Are you alright? I'm fine
- 你]事吧？ - ]事
Please pull up here
麻┠阍谇懊嫱Ｍ＼
Why?
质颤N？
I'll get off first
我先下
No, let me
不好，我先下
Mrs. Chan Ah Ping, you're back
- 太太 - 炳哥，你回砹耍
Visiting Mr.Chow?
- 是啊 - 找周先生？
Yes, I thought we'd have lunch but he isn't well
想找他喝茶，哪知道他病了
What's wrong with him?
怎N回事？
He's got fever, he's all alone
l，他老婆又不在家
So I'm gonna buy him something to eat
一人怪可z的，下去o他Ic什N吃
The congee downstairs is quite good
街口那家店，u的粥挺好的
He doesn't want congee
他不想吃粥
What does he want?
他想吃什N
Can't taste anything, so he wants sesame syrup
他f嘴e淡得慌，想吃芝麻糊
Damned troublesome
真yp
Amah
王，王
Mrs. Suen, she's hanging the washing on the roof
O太太，王上天台晾衣服去了
You're back
你回砹
Yes, you've been out?
@是上街回恚
My mother's birthday is coming up
是呀，下Y拜我^生日
So I took her to buy some fabric
我她去Ic布料做新衣
It took all day, I'm half dead
跑了一整天，舛即不上砹
And I had my hair done, is it nice?
道C了^，好看幔
Very nice
很漂亮
What are you cooking?
你在煮什N？
I had a sudden craving for sesame syrup
忽然想吃芝麻糊
That whole pot is for you
一大你怎N吃呀
I thought I might as well make a potful
反正煮了，大家一K吃吧
You're so thoughtful
你真客
Please try it I'll
- 硪煌氚 - 好啊
What a coincidence
@N巧
Going out?
是啊，上街幔
I'll buy some noodles, I'm starving
整晚]吃^|西了，下沓酝朦I
Hungary? Will you join me?
你I不I？一起啊？
No thanks
不了
Just off work?
@N晚才下班？
You must be very busy
公司很忙？
Actually, I've been to see a picture
就是]事做，所以看了鲭影
Really? How was it?
是幔好不好看？
So-so
RR虎虎
I used to like going to the pictures
我那耙劭措影
You had many hobbies before
你以前倒是挺多嗜好的
On your own, you are free to do lots of things
自己一人，大把rg， 想做什N就做什N
Everything changes when you marry
Y了婚就不一
It must be decided together
很多事情，一人作不了主
Right?
ΣΓ
I sometimes wonder what I'd be
有r候我想，要是F在]有Y婚
if I hadn't married
不知怎
Have you ever thought of that?
你也@酉幔
Maybe happier
可能比^_心吧
I didn't know married life would be
我以前都]有想到婚姻
so complicated
是@友}s
When you're single, you are only responsible to yourself
如果一人，自己做得好就蛄
Once you're married
可是人在一起r
doing well on your own is not enough
只有自己做得好是不虻
Don't brood on it, maybe he'll be back soon
e想太多了，等他回碓僬f吧
What about you?
你]事啊？
Actually, we're in the same boat
其我跟你不是一
But I don't brood on it
我只是不去想
It's not my fault
又不是我做e
I can't waste time wondering if I made mistakes
何必每天自己做e了什N
Life's too short for that
浪M自己rg
Something must change
我不想@酉氯
So what's your plan?
你有什N打算？
I want to write a martial-arts
@滋煳姨稍诖采戏武b小f
serial...
我想再
Actually, I've started one, I'll show it to you
已_了^，^商熳你看
Great
好啊
You like them too
你@N喜g看武b小f
so why not help me write it?
我一起吧
I wouldn't know how, I only read them
@怎N行，我只看，哪e
We would discuss it together
看嘛
Alright, I'll try my best
那好吧，我M量
I never thanked you for the sesame syrup
]多x你的芝麻糊呢
There's no need I was making it anyway
e客猓小意思嘛
Amazing, I was craving for some
f起碚媲
sesame syrup that day
好那天我很想吃芝麻糊
Really? What's a coincidence
是幔@N巧
It really was
是呀，就@N巧
I'll go for those noodles
我先去吃c|西
Again, halfway through dinner, he's drunk
老是@幼樱酒席吃到一半就醉倒
Disgusting
真
- I told you to stop - What can you do?
- 早feo他喝了 - 我有啥k法
It's me
是我
You scared me
死我了
How's Mr.Koo?
怎樱款先生有]有事？
Drunk, as usual
喝醉了吧
I didn't expect them back so early
怎@釉
Since you're trapped here, finish the noodles
反正]法子，不如先把面吃完再f
They'll probably go soon
我想他坐一壕妥
Want some soup?
加c幔
Mrs. Suen, playing here tonight
O太太，怎N在@打麻？
Yes, Mrs. Koo is dealing with her husband
太太f要看著她先生嘛
I could do that
早跟我f嘛，我碚疹他就行了
No, we should not trouble you
怎好意思呀
Think you'll play all night?
@痈吲d，看硪玩到天亮
No, we'll just play eight rounds
才不，多八圈
They'll play till morning?
你猜他不打到天亮？
Mrs. Suen says only eight rounds
O太太f只打八圈
You believe that?
你信不信？
You get some rest, I'll wake you when they leave
不如你瞌睡一，他散了我就叫你
And you?
那你呢？
I have a chapter to finish
我先把@段好
Where have you got to?
到哪海
The drunken master just showed up
大醉b出
When did he get written in?
怎N多了大醉b？
Just now
想到的
Mr.Chow, home so early?
周先生，@釉缇统鋈グ
I went out to buy some food
我下去Ic吃的
No work today?
你今天不用上班幔
I didn't feel so good, I'm staying home
有c不太舒服，告了一天假
A sick man shouldn't eat all that sticky rice
不舒服吃@N多糯米u
Some of it's for later
省得晚上再出去I
Don't stuff yourself
心吃瘟
Good morning
周先生
Good morning, finished your game?
你早，散隽幔O太太？
Not yet, but Mr.Yang has to work
]有呢，钕壬要k公，他先走了
Mr.Tsai is coming to replace him
不^蔡先生R上就
Did you call the office for me?
有]有臀掖螂回公司假？
Yes
打^了
What did you tell them?
你怎Nf的
That you weren't feeling well
f你病了
Did them ask who you were?
他有]有你是l
No
]有
Probably took me for your husband
多半以槲沂悄阏煞虬
Mr.Ho knows that he's away
何先生知道他出T了
Pretend he's come back
就f他已回砗昧
Maybe we're being too cautious?
都是自己自己
I'm always round anyway
平日我也常^
We shouldn't have panicked
有什N好o的
Well, they did turn up without warning
@很yf，他突然之g回
What would they assume?
不知道他怎Ny想
We can't put a foot wrong
所以真的不能走e一步
You can go
走吧
Amah Mrs. Chan, you're back very late
- 王 - 太太，怎N@油恚
I had a lot of work today
是呀，今天公司事情多
I didn't see you leave this morning
怎N今早]看你上班？
I had breakfast with my mother
今天很早s了喝茶
You weren't here when I left
我出去的r候你]
Where's Mrs. Suen?
O太太呢？
Asleep, she played mahjong all day
她搓麻⒋甑教炝粒才睡
Be quiet, don't wake her Alright
- e吵她了 - 好的
Mrs. Chan, is your leg alright?
呀，太太，你的_好吧
It's these new shoes
]什N，新鞋子太窄，D_了
Why a special dinner tonight?
致镎我吃？
Since you won't take your share of
今天出稿M，你那一份你又不收
the writing fee
只好你吃了
None of my business
其不P我的事
All I did was give you some thoughts
我在旁打打鼓而已
Someone else is asking for a serial too
我也S多一家蠹
There'll be more work soon
今天有人打砑s稿
Really? So quickly
是幔磕翘好了
Isn't the workload too much?
你付得了幔
That's why I'm looking for a new place
所以想找一地方
What for?
做什N？
To write in
|西
lt'll be more convenient
@幽阋葬嵘矶挤奖泓c嘛
There's nothing between us
m然我之g]什N
but I don't want gossip
但是我不想e人`你
What do you think?
你X得怎樱
Why waste money?
太浪M了
You don't need me
其都是你自己的
you can write on your own
何必多此一e呢
Who do you want?
喂，找l呀？
Chow Mo-Wan?
周慕？
He hasn't been in for several days
他]上班好滋炝
We're looking for him too
我也到在找他
May I know who's calling?
你是哪位啊？
Any message?
要留幔
It's no trouble, goodbye
哦，不用x，多戆
Please get this to Accounts
@文件R上送去部
And have the air-conditioner serviced tomorrow
有，冷C明天叫人砜纯
Mr.Ho
好，何先生
No need to stay if everything's done
]什N事了，你可以走了
I'll lock up Yes
- T我礞iD - 好的
Hello?
喂
Where are you?
你在哪e啊？
I'll come again tomorrow
我明天再砜茨
No need, I'll be alright after some rest
我歇商炀]事
It's no trouble
不要o，才一汗Ψ
I'll bring you some food, what would you like?
我o你Ic吃的，你想吃什N
Whatever
S便
Then I'll leave now, get some rest
那我就走了，你早c休息
Call me when you get home
回去o我
Let it ring three times then hang up
用不著f，三就好
Alright
好
I didn't think you'd come
我]想^你
We won't be like them
我不跟他一拥
See you tomorrow
明天
Tell me honestly
你老告V我
Do you have a mistress?
你外面是不是有女人？
You're crazy
神病
Who told you I had?
l跟你f的
Never mind who
你e管
Do you or don't you?
你是不是有了女人
No
]有
Don't lie
不要_我
Look at me
你看著我，你看著我
I'm asking you, do you have a mistress
我你，你外面是不是有女人？
Yes
是
That's no reaction
你怎N了？
If he admits it outright
他已承J在外面有女人
let him have it
你打得@Np
I wasn't expecting he would admit it so easily
我]想到他回答得@忧脆
I didn't know how to react
我不知道怎Nk
One more time, alright?
再硪淮伟
Tell me frankly
你老回答我
Do you have a mistress?
你外面是不是有女人？
You're crazy
神病
Who told you that?
l跟你f的？
Never mind that, do you or don't you?
你e管，你是不是有女人？
No
]有
Don't lie
你不要_我
Tell me
你告V我
Look at me, do you have a mistress?
你看著我，是不是有女人？
Yes
是
Are you alright?
你]事吧
I didn't expect it to hurt so much
我]想到真的@心
This is just a rehearsal
我而已，又不是真的
He won't really admit it so readily
就算是真的他也不J
It's alright, don't take it so hard
]事的，e@
You've been out a lot lately
你最近好像酬挺多的？
Yes
是啊
It's right to enjoy yourself while you're young
年op呢，出去散散心是的
But don't overdo it
不^得有分寸
When will your husband be back?
你先生r回恚
Soon
他快回砹
In future, don't let him travel so much
等他回砟兀e再他老出T
A couple should spend time together
煞蚱藿常分_呢，不大好
Don't you agree?
你f幔
Good night
晚安
Will you come over tonight?
你今天晚上^不^恚
What for?
做什N？
The editor's hounding me, he says I'm too slow
@商旖o催稿，f我得慢
I need your help, when can you come?
^兔κ职。磕c可以？
Not anytime soon
我想@子我不^砹
Why not?
怎N了？
Mrs. Suen lectured me last night
昨晚回家，O太太f了拙
What did he say?
她f你什N
Rather not say
我不想v
We shouldn't see so much of each other
反正@子我是少c面吧
Mrs. Chan, going out for noodles again?
太太，又要去I面啊？
Not tonight, I'll make myself something
今天不去了
Join us, we're having vegetable won-tons
S便弄c什N吃的就算了
Alright
那好的
- No lunch today, Mr.Ho? - No
- 何先生]出去吃午？ - ]有
Now one Mr.Zhou call you
才有位周先生打找你
He wants you to call him back
叫你回o他
Thank you
xx
- Back from work? - Yes
- 下班啦？ - 是呀
- Strange weather Isn't it - Yes
- @真是大雨呀 - 是呀
Been here long?
在@赫竞芫昧耍
Just a while
一毫T了
I don't think it'll stop soon
我想得下好一
Wait for me
你等等我
I'll see you home
我送你回去
We'd better not be seen together
人看，又多了
Then you go first
那N你先回去
If they see your umbrella
他J得你的
They'll know I was with you
我沃回去，不也一樱
I wasn't thinking
@也是，我倒]想到
You go first, I'll wait a while
你先回去吧，我待一壕突
I'll keep you company
我陪你
Did you try to call me?
你找^我？
I wasn't sure you got the message
以槟阃事忘了告V你
Could you get me a boat ticker?
想找你I船票
To where?
你要去e的地方？
Ah Ping wrote from Singapore
阿炳磉^很多信
They're short of staff, he'd like me to go and help
f那缺人手，要我去退忙
How long will you stay?
打算去多久？
Don't know, I'll play it be ear
不知道，去了再f吧
Why rush off to Singapore?
怎N突然想去新加坡？
A change of scene...
想Q―下h境
I've had enough of the gossip
免得著太多的f言fZ
We know it's not true, so why worry?
我自己知道我]什N不就行了
I used to think that too
原砦乙策@酉
and it didn't worry me
所以不怕e人ff
I thought we wouldn't be like them
我相信我自己不像他那
But I was wrong
原的
You won't leave your husband
我知道你不x_你丈夫
So I'd rather go away
我想x_一下
I didn't think you'd fall in love with me
我]有想^你真的喜g我
I didn't either
我也]有想^
I was only curious to know how it started
我一直在想，他是怎娱_始的
Now I know
F在我明白了
Feelings can creep up just like that
原砗芏嗍虑槎歼@
I thought I was in control
我以樽约]有什N
But I hate to think of our husband coming home
但是_始心你丈夫r回
I wish he'd stay away
最好不要回
I'm so bad
我知道@酉氩
Will you do me one favour?
你能不能臀乙忙
What?
做什N？
I want to be prepared
我想有c心理
You'd better not see me again
以後不要再找我了
Is your husband back?
你老公他回砹耍
Yes
是啊
Am I hopeless?
我真]用
Not really
不是啊
I won't see you again
我不再找你了
Keep a closer eye on your husband
好好地守著你的丈夫
Please
e@
Don't be serious it's only a rehearsal
f了著的嘛
Don't cry
e哭
This isn't real
@又不是真的
I don't want to go home tonight
我今天晚上不想回家
Mei-Yi wants to dedicate a song
美xco好朋友嘧泻臀奈
to her honeymooning friends
祝他成功
And Mrs. Cheung wishes the best to
又co同屋的太太收
her neighbors
祝家庭幸福
And Mr.Chan, now on business in Japan
有一位在日本公值年先生
wants to wish his wife
c@首歌o他太太
a happy birthday
祝她生日快罚工作利
So let's all enjoy Zhou Xuan singing
F在大家一起欣p，周璇唱的
In Full Bloom
花拥哪耆A
It's me
是我
If there's an extra ticket
如果有多一船票
Would you go with me?
你不跟我一起走？
It's me
是我
If there's an extra ticket
如果有多一船票
Would you go with me?
你不我一起走？
Mr.Chow has gone to work
哈_？周先生不在，他上班去了
Any message?
有要D_幔
You're welcome
不用x，拜拜
Has anyone been in my room?
是不是有人M^我房g？
No
]有呀
Something's missing
]有？我G了|西
What?
G了什N呀
In the old days
你知不知道，那暗娜
If someone had a secret they didn't want to share
要是心e有了秘密，不想e人知道
You know what they did?
你知不知道他怎幼觯
Have no idea
我怎N知道？
They went up to a mountain, found a tree
他跑到山上找一棵
Carved a hole in it
在渖贤洞
And whispered the secret into the hole
然後把秘密全fM去
Then they covered it with mud
再用泥巴封起
And leave the secret there forever
那秘密就永h留在那棵溲e，]人知道
What a pain, I'd just go to get laid
@有量啵找女人l一下不更好
Not everyone's like you
l都像你呀
I'm just an average guy
f得是呀，像我@拥娜
I don't have secrets like you
是直c子，哪淼男氖卵剑
You bottle things up
你可不同，什N都往心eR
Tell me something
f砺嘛
I don't have secrets
我哪有心事
Come off it, buddy
你em我啦，一雠笥
I won't tell anyone
我不跟e人f的
Hello, Singapore Daily
喂，你好，星洲日
Hold on
等等
Mr.Chow, call for you
哥，
Thanks
xx
Hello
喂
- Who is it? - It is me
- l呀？ - 王，是我啊
- Mrs. Chan, long time no see - Yes
- 太太，好久]了 - 是呀
- Amah, who's there? - Mrs. Suen
- 王，什N人呀 - O太太
What brings you here?
哎呀，你怎N^戆。
It's been a while
我想@N久]砜茨
I was nearby
今天好磉@附近
so I thought I'd bring your boat ticket
特意把船票o你送
And a small gift
你吃的
You shouldn't have, it's nice just to see you
哎呀，上碜坐就好了， @涌猓又破M
The place is in such a mess
你看@屋ey七八糟的
Already started packing?
你已在收拾了？
It's hopeless,
已收拾好滋炝
I can't bear to throw things away
|西太多，有些又尾坏萌
- Let's find you a seat - OK
- 坐的地方都]有，到@坐 - 好啊
- Have some tea - Thank you
- 瞬 - xx，王
Eat with us, Mrs. Chan, I'm going to the market
你今天e走，在@e吃晚，我去I菜
I can't, I have work waiting
不行呢，我得回公司kc事
Don't rush off
你致锛敝走
if you don't eat here
你不留在@撼燥
Mrs. Suen will be upset
太太要不高d的，太太？
Amah, pour me some tea too
，你替我倒杯茶
How's your husband?
先生好幔
He's fine, thank you
挺好的，有心了
How long will you be away?
你打算走多久？
I don't know
我也不缘
If I like it, I might stay
要是住的T呢我就不回砹
Why?
槭颤N？
My daughter worries about the situation in Hong Kong
我女赫fF在香港@Ny
She worry about I stay alone in Hong Kong
我自己一人在@她不放心
I don't want to leave
我倒是尾坏秒x_香港的
Since the Koos left
不^自念先生他搬走了以後
I don't have my mahjong partners anymore
搓麻⒁]搭伴
And my daughter needs help with her kids in the US
想想呢，是到美去o女Ш⒆铀懔
What about this place?
@房子怎Nk？
I'm not sure
正榱诉@X筋嘛
I don't want to sell it
u出去呢真不蔚
So I might rent it out
想想是租o人家吧
How much would you want?
你打算租多少X？
You're interested?
？你有意思租幔
You could have it at a discount
租o你我可就放心了， 我便宜c租o你啦
I'll think about it
我想想看
Mrs. Suen, your tea
太太，瞬
Who lives next door now?
α耍F在是什N人住在隔壁？
I don't really know them
我也不大缘茫不像以前，都]往
The Koos were almost like family
以前跟先生太太不知多狒[
It was so nice then
像一家人一樱想起硪查_心
wasn't it?
你f是幔
Yes
是啊
Let's sit over here
^磉@坐
Yes?
你找哪位？
Is Mr.Koo in?
先生在不在？
He moved long ago
先生？搬了好久了
Do you know where he is?
知不知道搬到哪喝チ耍
You know him well?
你跟他很熟幔
I used to live here
我那白≡谶@e
Is Mrs. Suen still next door?
O太太住在隔壁幔
She's gone, it's too chaotic
也搬了，F在y成@
Everyone's running away
能走的不走幔
So who lives there now?
F在隔壁住著什N人？
I am not sure
我也不太清楚
A woman and her son
好像就是一女人е她鹤
The kid is cute
那小孩子U可鄣
No address in the Philippines
他菲律e的地址我]找著
Just his son's phone number
只有他鹤拥碾
- I can't accept this - How this
- 你拿回去 - @怎行
Please, you must
小意思，不客
- Thank you, then - Bye
- 那Nxx了 - 慢走
That era has passed
那r代已^去
Nothing that belonged to
凫赌r代的一切
it exists any more
都不存在了
Are you ready?
庸生，好了]？
- Okay - Let's go
- 好了 - 快c
The presidential corps waits at Pochentong Airport
柬埔寨首都C錾
Prince Norodom Sihanouk and Queen sisowath Kossamak
皇室人T上前
come forward to greet General De Gaulle
迎接戴高④
It's ten kilometres from Pochentong to Phnom Penh
公路上列g迎
200,000 people line the route
人潮_二十f人
A welcome unprecedented in the history of the Kingdom
下前所未有的一